We are talking about the home office and how to be productive.
So for me I've found that environment is very important.
When I first started working remotely or from home I found that I just kind of would work wherever I could.
I had a laptop.
I was sitting on the couch with the TV on one day and maybe I would be sitting in my room writing, typing while I am sitting on my bed another day and what I came to find out was that just really wasn't conducive for me being productive so what I did was I got a room all to myself.
This is my home office.
I designate it as my space.
I decorated it the way I wanted to in a way that made me feel calm and allows me to think clearly.
I think that environment is very important for productivity.
Looking back I don't even know how I got anything done sitting on the couch with people walking around, talking to me, interrupting me.
I got things done but I can tell you it wasn't nearly to the level where I am able to be productive now so I would highly recommend even if you don't have an entire room that you can stake out for yourself.
I do think that is idea.
Even if you can't do that though, make sure that there is a corner or an area of the house that is yours.
That is your work station.
That is where you go when you are working and that your family and your loved ones, your children, whoever might be a distraction know that when you are there working, you're working and that is your work time and just kind of, if you set those boundaries right from the start then it should be a lot easier for you down the road and when you sit there you will have that psychological trigger of oh, this is my work station, this is where I work.
It just kind of helps you over time be a lot more productive.